

Shahram Rezasade

Private Equity M&A **Entrepreneur**

10 years 4 years **Forever**

Contact

Munich, Germany

+49 162 713 7933

Shahram Rezasade

Education

Master of Business Administration and Corporate Finance (German Diploma) RWTH University of Science and Technology, Aachen, Germany

Languages

English Fluent German Native Persian Native Italien Medium

About me

I am a passionate entrepreneur, skilled Private Equity investor, and a hands-on growth leader. With over 20 years, my career spans three areas: Strategic Consultancy, Private Equity, and Management.

I excel particularly at financial and commercial due diligence. understanding new markets, identifying business development opportunities, building go-to-market strategies, and building and cultivating growth teams.

As a former founder and manager of VC and PE-backed growth companies, I've equipped myself with excellent people management skills, and the ability to quickly gain market shares, and simultaneously manage multiple projects.

Experience

General Manager Germany

AllTrails - / Munich, San Fransisco

AUG 2022 - DEC 2022

Managing the world's largest outdoor app (backed by Permira) with more than 40 million users. My job is to create growth, build partnerships, help localize the product, and execute a tailored marketing and PR strategy. All Trails decided to cease its market entry in Germany and cut costs in its international expansion team.

General Manager DACH

AUG 2021 - AUG 2022

DOCKR Mobility - / Munich, Amsterdam

Launched DOCKR, the world leader of Cargobikes as a Service, in DACH. Acquired the largest customers in instant commerce like Flink, Gorillas, Foodpanda. Built a service infrastructure and strategic technical and financial partnerships in Germany, set the strategy for local marketing campaigns, and hired a team of sales, growth, and operations. Set the business plan and built the bridge to HQ culturally.

Co-Founder, CEO

JAN 2019 - JUL 2021

Tiptab.com and BRIDG.app - FinTech / Berlin

Co-founded tiptab, a digital tipping company, and BRIDG, a marketplace for revenue-based financing. Started from recruiting co-founders to building MVPs, hiring technical teams, raising capital and managing investors, acquiring initial customers, and keeping the company liquid. Ultimately, we failed for various reasons but we banked lessons the hard way and deepened our love for FinTechs.

Country Manager DACH and Africa

JUN 2018 - DEC 2018

Funderbeam.com - FinTech / Munich, London

Competitor of Angellist and CartaX with a secondary shares marketplace built on Blockchain. Led market entry in the DACH region and Africa. Built the regulatory framework, secured initial customers, and led acquisition negotiations with Frankfurt Stock Exchange. We

Skills

- Financial/Commercial Due Diligence
- Business Development
- Expansion and growth
- Marketing and PR
- Financial analysis and planning
- Strategic thinking
- Building trustworthy partnerships
- Fundraising and negotiations
- Attention to detail
- Ability to learn new skills

Interests

Interested in FinTechs, nature conservancy, and sustainable farming. Reading science, technology, and future studies. Passion for Tennis and Hiking.

Book

Praktiker-Handbuch Basel II ISBN-13: 978-3791019857

Co-authored an award-winning book on the regulatory framework of the financial and banking system (Basel II)

Links: Content. Amazon.

Podcast

A new way to finance and fund growth of SaaS companies Link: Spotify

Award

Intel Innovation Award for AI-Based solution for diagnosis of lung diseases Link: Intel Innovation Awar

had to withdraw from mainland Europe after Brexit (we couldn't passport our FCA license).

Investment Partner

JAN 2015 - DEC 2016

Bavaria Industries Capital - Private Equity / Munich

A €500m listed Private Equity fund focusing on business transformation, turnaround buyouts, and complex carveouts. Led transactions from sourcing to structuring acquisition financing, to exit.

Investment Partner

JUN 2010 - DEC 2014

Industriepartner Capital - Private Equity / Düsseldorf

Co-founded an evergreen €20m turnaround Private Equity fund and raised capital from two major German family offices. Created Germany's No.1 player of connected car solutions through buy & build

Investment Director

NOV 2007 - JUN 2010

Equity Partners - Private Equity / Dusseldorf

A €500m Private Equity fund focusing on Co-Investments. Led Due Diligence teams, structured and presented buyouts to the board, co-invested alongside large PE funds like KKR, HG Capital, Gilde.

Investment Professional

JAN 2007 - NOV 2007

Triton Partners - Private Equity / Frankfurt

An €8bn Private Equity fund focusing on large-cap complex transactions. Worked in portfolio management responsible for operational improvement programs at different portfolio companies.

Manager

OCT 2002 - JAN 2007

KPMG - Strategic M&A Consultancy / Europe

Advised international blue-chip companies like Bayer, BASF, Henkel on strategic acquisitions, divestments, and repositionings. Led due diligence projects with a focus on financial due diligence, financial modeling, and debt advisory.

Analyst

JAN 2000 - DEC 2000

Morgan Stanley - Investment Banking / Frankfurt

Financial modeling, institutional and large credit advisory division.

Side Projects

Unpaid advisor

JAN 2017 - AUG 2019

Gates Foundation, United Nations / Cape Town, Munich

Advised the World Food Programme and the Gates Foundation on startup investments in emerging markets to fight world hunger

Co-Founder, Chairman

OCT 2019 - Present

accrad.com - HealthTech / Cape Town, Munich

Al project to detect clinical diseases including COVID and Tuberculosis on chest radiographs in Africa. Winner of the Intel Innovation Award.